♪Holding hands silently as flowers fall and winds rise♪
♪يمسك الأيدي بصمت بينما تتساقط الزهور وترتفع الرياح♪
♪Dark tresses cascade like mountains. Dreams intertwine♪
♪خصلات داكنة تتدلى كالجبال. تتشابك الأحلام♪
♪Painting realms, clouds in palm, my brushwork for you♪
♪رسم العوالم، السحب في راحة اليد، فرشاتي لك♪
♪Light and shadow overlap my name across time and space♪
♪يتداخل الضوء والظل مع اسمي عبر الزمان والمكان♪
♪Across starry rivers, I chase dreams afar♪
♪عبر الأنهار المرصعة بالنجوم، أطارد الأحلام البعيدة♪
♪Arms spread wide, falling through heaven and earth♪
♪أذرع مفتوحة على مصراعيها، تسقط عبر السماء والأرض♪
♪The rhythm of breath and heartbeat♪
♪إيقاع التنفس ونبض القلب♪
♪A meeting of the souls♪
♪لقاء الأرواح♪
♪Through shifting seas and lands, I'd know you still♪
♪من خلال البحار والأراضي المتغيرة، سأظل أعرفك♪
♪Eyes bright as moonlit skies, untouched by worldly dust♪
♪عيون لامعة مثل سماء مضاءة بالقمر، غير متأثرة بغبار العالم♪
♪Smiling gazes write eternity♪
♪النظرات المبتسمة تكتب الخلود♪
=The Crush=
=السحق=
=Episode 22= (Turning the Tide, Truth Revealed)
=الحلقة 22= (تغيير المسار، كشف الحقيقة)
(Gu's Tea House)
(بيت الشاي جو)
Miss Niaoniao,
الآنسة نياونياو،
our business
أعمالنا
has always been with Li's Tea Estate.
لقد كان دائمًا مع Li's Tea Estate.
Why
لماذا
is the contract with Li's Tea Estate
هو العقد مع شركة لي تي إستيت
being signed with Gu's Tea Estate now?
هل تم التوقيع مع Gu's Tea Estate الآن؟
Mr. Li,
السيد لي،
now that I'm part of the Li family,
الآن بعد أن أصبحت جزءًا من عائلة لي،
there's no distinction between Gu's Tea Estate
لا يوجد فرق بين Gu's Tea Estate
and Li's Tea Estate.
ومزرعة الشاي لي.
For the new contract,
بالنسبة للعقد الجديد،
I'll offer both of you
سأعرض عليكما كلتيهما
another percent discount.
خصم آخر بنسبة مئوية.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
Since you said that,
وبما أنك قلت ذلك،
we'll entrust
سوف نعهد
our business to Gu's Tea Estate from now on.
أعمالنا مع Gu's Tea Estate من الآن فصاعدا.
We'll rely on
سوف نعتمد على
your generous support.
دعمكم السخي.
Hold it!
إمسكها!
Let me see
دعني أرى
who's using Li's Tea Estate
من يستخدم مزرعة شاي لي؟
to swindle people here!
لخداع الناس هنا!
Madam, why have you come?
سيدتي لماذا أتيت؟
If I hadn't come,
لو لم آتي،
you'd have hollowed out Li's Tea Estate completely!
لقد قمت بتفريغ مزرعة شاي لي بالكامل!
When did Li's Tea Estate's business
متى بدأت أعمال شركة لي للشاي؟
get transferred to Gu's Tea Estate?
هل سيتم نقلك إلى Gu's Tea Estate؟
You're not worthy
أنت لا تستحق
to stamp our seal!
لختم ختمنا!
Madam, what are you talking about?
سيدتي، ما الذي تتحدثين عنه؟
Now that I'm married into the Li family,
الآن بعد أن تزوجت من عائلة لي،
there's no separation between Li's Tea Estate
لا يوجد فصل بين مزرعة شاي لي
and Gu's Tea Estate.
ومزرعة الشاي جو.
A mere concubine
أن يكون لديك محظيات
has no right
ليس له حق
to represent Li's Tea Estate publicly.
لتمثيل شركة Li's Tea Estate علنًا.
Our business
أعمالنا
isn't yours to manage!
ليس من حقك إدارتها!
You two have been our longtime partners.
لقد كنتما شريكين لنا منذ فترة طويلة.
How could you humor this concubine's antics?
كيف يمكنك أن تتقبل تصرفات هذه المحظية؟
Out of our past relationship,
من علاقتنا الماضية،
I'll let this slide.
سأترك هذا الأمر.
You two may leave now.
يمكنكم المغادرة الآن.
Can't you distinguish your real friend?
هل لا تستطيع التمييز بين صديقك الحقيقي؟
Madam,
سيدتي،
outside the Li Manor,
خارج قصر لي،
your tantrums and unreasonable demands
نوبات الغضب والمطالب غير المعقولة
won't be tolerated.
لن يتم التسامح معها.
Business is just business.
الأعمال هي مجرد أعمال.
These two owners want my written commitment.
يريد هذان المالكان التزامي المكتوب.
After all,
بعد كل شيء،
who would refuse profits?
من يرفض الأرباح؟
Even if Zixuan isn't managing affairs now,
حتى لو لم يكن زيكسوان يدير الشؤون الآن،
don't think you can deceive everyone.
لا أعتقد أنك قادر على خداع الجميع.
If this goes to court,
إذا وصل هذا الأمر إلى المحكمة،
you might spend the rest of your life in prison!
ربما تقضي بقية حياتك في السجن!
If we actually go to court,
إذا ذهبنا إلى المحكمة فعليا،
all our past dealings
كل تعاملاتنا السابقة
will come to light.
سوف يخرج إلى النور.
I can manage,
انا قادر على الإدارة
but if you go to prison,
ولكن إذا ذهبت إلى السجن،
what will happen to Young Master Zimo?
ماذا سيحدث للسيد الشاب زيمو؟
You...
أنت...
You vicious woman!
يا لك من امرأة شريرة!
Don't push things too far.
لا تدفع الأمور إلى أبعد من اللازم.
The tea estate's business
أعمال مزرعة الشاي
will have nothing to do with your family from now on.
لن يكون له أي علاقة بعائلتك من الآن فصاعدا.
Oh,
أوه،
I forgot to remind you.
لقد نسيت أن أذكرك.
Losing this business
خسارة هذا العمل
cuts off the cash flow.
يقطع التدفق النقدي.
The workers' wages
أجور العمال
and Young Master Zimo's tavern debts
وديون حانة السيد الشاب زيمو
will become unpaid.
سوف تصبح غير مدفوعة الأجر.
You should hurry back
ينبغي عليك العودة بسرعة
and sell off your valuables
وبيع ممتلكاتك الثمينة
before outsiders strip the manor bare
قبل أن يجرد الغرباء القصر من كل محتوياته
and leave you homeless.
ويتركك بلا مأوى.
You...
أنت...
What a lively scene!
يا له من مشهد حيوي!
Miss Gu.
السيدة جو.
You didn't inform us about
لم تخبرنا عن
such a grand opening ceremony?
حفل افتتاح كبير كهذا؟
Haven't you noticed
ألم تلاحظ؟
something suspicious about Niaoniao?
هل هناك شيء مريب حول نياونياو؟
Given my tea skills,
نظرا لمهاراتي في تحضير الشاي،
could I replace Mr. Zixuan in the competition?
هل بإمكاني أن أحل محل السيد زيكسوان في المنافسة؟
From overthrowing Mr. Wang of Tianxiang Tea House
من الإطاحة بالسيد وانغ من بيت الشاي تيانشيانغ
to revealing herself
لتكشف عن نفسها
as your savior...
كمخلصك...
I wore white clothes and tied up my hair
ارتديت ملابس بيضاء وربطت شعري
for better mobility.
لتحسين القدرة على الحركة.
Now, she's brought back to the manor by your mother.
والآن، تم إرجاعها إلى القصر من قبل والدتك.
When connecting all these events,
عند ربط كل هذه الأحداث،
it appears
يبدو أنه
Niaoniao was taken advantage of by your mother.
لقد تم استغلال نياونياو من قبل والدتك.
But actually,
ولكن في الواقع،
I think
أظن
your mother
والدتك
is a pawn used by Niaoniao.
هو بيدق يستخدمه نياونياو.
But what's her purpose in doing this?
ولكن ما هو هدفها من القيام بهذا؟
I haven't figured that out yet.
لم أفهم ذلك بعد.
But I do have a plan.
ولكن لدي خطة.
Will you trust me?
هل ستثق بي؟
I'll come to see you again tomorrow.
سوف آتي لرؤيتك مرة أخرى غدا.
(Gu's Tea House)
(بيت الشاي جو)
You two,
انتما الاثنان
today's matter is our family affair.
موضوع اليوم هو شأن عائلتنا.
Nothing to do with you.
لا علاقة لك بذلك.
Miss Niaoniao forged the seal
قامت الآنسة نيونياو بتزوير الختم
and imitated my handwriting.
وقلّد خط يدي.
Tomorrow, I'll report it to officials.
سأبلغ المسؤولين غدًا.
By then, your contract
بحلول ذلك الوقت، عقدك
will naturally become invalid.
سوف تصبح غير صالحة بطبيعة الحال.
But don't worry.
ولكن لا تقلق.
Our business with you
أعمالنا معك
- Are you okay? - won't change.
- هل أنت بخير؟ - لن يتغير.
You two may leave for today.
يمكنكم المغادرة اليوم.
We're leaving.
نحن نغادر.
Miss Niaoniao,
الآنسة نياونياو،
from the very beginning,
منذ البداية،
I've been suspicious
لقد كنت أشك
that you weren't Zixuan's savior.
أنك لم تكن منقذ زيكسوان.
Now, I should address you as Gu Nianyao.
الآن، يجب أن أخاطبك باسم Gu Nianyao.
The Gu family of Jiangnan.
عائلة جو من جيانغنان.
Gu's Tea Estate.
مزرعة شاي جو.
Am I right?
هل انا على حق؟
What did you call her?
ماذا أسميتها؟
Miss Gu.
السيدة جو.
You came for your family incident, right?
لقد أتيت من أجل حادثة عائلتك، أليس كذلك؟
My father told me
لقد أخبرني والدي
about it.
حوله.
It had weighed on his conscience.
لقد كان ذلك يثقل على ضميره.
Your tea emphasized a lingering aroma in the bowl.
لقد أكد الشاي الخاص بك على الرائحة المتبقية في الوعاء.
But storing tea too long
لكن تخزين الشاي لفترة طويلة
would allow fungi to grow.
سوف يسمح للفطريات بالنمو.
Though the amount was small,
على الرغم من أن المبلغ كان صغيرا،
it wasn't the cause of the illness in the court.
ولم يكن هذا هو سبب المرض في المحكمة.
My father hesitated
تردد والدي
about whether to report it.
حول ما إذا كان ينبغي الإبلاغ عنه.
Considering your tea business's scale,
بالنظر إلى حجم أعمال الشاي الخاصة بك،
if it wasn't clarified,
إذا لم يتم توضيح ذلك،
problems would arise later.
قد تنشأ المشاكل في وقت لاحق.
So my father reported truthfully,
فأخبرني والدي بصدق،
but he emphasized
لكنه أكد
the small amount couldn't cause illness.
كمية صغيرة لا يمكن أن تسبب المرض.
But unexpectedly,
ولكن بشكل غير متوقع،
the imperial court
البلاط الإمبراطوري
still shut down your business.
لا تزال تغلق عملك.
After my father returned,
بعد عودة والدي،
he fell gravely ill.
لقد أصيب بمرض خطير.
But he still had someone
ولكن لا يزال لديه شخص ما
send you
أرسل لك
all the money he could spare
كل الأموال التي يمكنه توفيرها
to ensure your livelihood.
لضمان معيشتك.
Li Zixuan,
لي زيكسوان،
even now,
حتى الآن،
you still pretend to be righteous?
هل مازلت تتظاهر بأنك صالح؟
If you'd truly helped us in crisis back then
لو كنت ساعدتنا حقًا في الأزمة في ذلك الوقت
by sending the money,
عن طريق إرسال الأموال،
how could my family have been destroyed?
كيف يمكن تدمير عائلتي؟
Now that I'm in your hands,
الآن بعد أن أصبحت بين يديك،
I've lost.
لقد خسرت.
I admit it.
أعترف بذلك.
But
لكن
save your hypocritical speeches.
أنقذوا خطاباتكم المنافقه.
Even as a ghost, I will
حتى كشبح، سأفعل
forever remember your family.
تذكر عائلتك إلى الأبد.
Miss Gu.
السيدة جو.
Miss.
يفتقد.
This is
هذا هو
all my jewelry.
كل مجوهراتي.
I couldn't convert them to cash.
لم أستطع تحويلها إلى نقود.
Please take it.
من فضلك خذها.
Leave quickly.
إرحل بسرعة.
Get out of Haiqing.
اخرج من هايتشينج.
What's the meaning of this?
ما معنى هذا؟
They'll send you to the yamen tomorrow.
سوف يرسلونك إلى يامن غدًا.
I brought you here.
لقد أحضرتك إلى هنا.
If this goes to court,
إذا وصل هذا الأمر إلى المحكمة،
many matters
العديد من الأمور
will implicate me.
سوف تورطني.
You want me to leave,
تريدني أن أرحل
but in this vast world,
ولكن في هذا العالم الواسع،
where can I find refuge?
أين يمكنني أن أجد ملجأ؟
I'm already homeless.
أنا بالفعل بلا مأوى.
Even if I face the officials tomorrow,
حتى لو واجهت المسؤولين غدًا،
I'll fight to the bitter end.
سأقاتل حتى النهاية المريرة.
You people framed my family back then.
لقد قمتم بتوريط عائلتي في ذلك الوقت.
Tomorrow,
غداً،
I'll return every deed
سأعيد كل فعل
to you in full.
لك بالكامل.
Your hatred for the Li family
كراهيتك لعائلة لي
truly can't be let go of?
حقا لا يمكن التخلي عنها؟
A ten-year-old girl
فتاة تبلغ من العمر عشر سنوات
watched her entire family perish.
شاهدت عائلتها بأكملها تموت.
She can survive alone by pleasing men.
إنها تستطيع البقاء على قيد الحياة بمفردها من خلال إرضاء الرجال.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
dozens of our family lives,
العشرات من أفراد عائلتنا،
who will atone for them?
فمن يكفر عنهم؟
Let your hatred for the Li family
دع كراهيتك لعائلة لي
all fall upon me.
كلها تقع عليّ.
What do you mean by this?
ماذا تقصد بهذا؟
I'm the one who failed your family.
أنا من خذل عائلتك.
Back then, Master Li
في ذلك الوقت، كان السيد لي
truly exhausted all our family's wealth
لقد استنفدت حقا كل ثروة عائلتنا
to send aid to your family.
لإرسال المساعدات إلى عائلتك.
But at that time,
ولكن في ذلك الوقت،
I had just conceived Zimo.
لقد حملت للتو بزيمو.
If the Li family had collapsed,
لو انهارت عائلة لي،
what would have become of Zimo?
ماذا كان سيحدث لزيمو؟
I
أنا
secretly intercepted
تم اعتراضها سرا
that money
تلك الأموال
and returned it to our accounts
وأعادوها إلى حساباتنا
while Master Li was gravely ill.
بينما كان السيد لي مريضًا بشكل خطير.
All of this was my doing.
كل هذا كان من صنعي.
Direct your hatred for the Li family
وجه كراهيتك لعائلة لي
all at me.
كلها علي.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
I'll show mercy?
هل سأظهر الرحمة؟
I only hope
انا فقط اتمنى
that after avenging your hatred,
أنه بعد الانتقام من كراهيتك،
you can start anew
يمكنك البدء من جديد
and live an ordinary life.
وعيش حياة عادية.
- Miss Gu!
- آنسة جو!